Bruce Russell Papers
Bruce Russell Papers
1891-1964
Russell, Bruce, 1903-1963.
28 linear ft.
Primarily original artwork by Russell (particularly his editorial cartoons but also comic strips, sports and entertainment illustrations) and by nearly 100 cartoonists including: Carey Orr, Bill Mauldin, Herblock and Charles Schulz. The collection also includes correspondence; clippings of Russell's work; memorabilia including photographs and biographical information; idea files for specific topics containing clippings and printed material; and writings
149559
Biographical History
Bruce Alexander Russell (1903-1963) was a Pulitzer Prize winning American cartoonist who spent over 30 years at the Los Angeles Times.
Russell was born in Los Angeles on August 4, 1903, the son of Alexander and Flora (Saunders) Russell. In 1921 Russell graduated from Los Angeles Polytechnic High School and in 1926 he received a degree from the University of California at Los Angeles, where he had drawn cartoons for the university newspaper, The Daily Bruin, and for The California Grizzly. Russell began his professional career at the Los Angeles Evening Herald. His early work appeared in various national publications, among them College Humor and Collier's, as well as in The California Pelican, published in Berkeley. In 1927 Russell joined the Los Angeles Times art staff as a sports and theater cartoonist and also sketched for the paper's illustrated magazine. During this period he created the popular Associated Press comic strip Rollo Rollingstone, which ran from 1930 to 1933. In 1934 Russell became the editorial cartoonist for the Los Angeles Times, a position he retained until his death nearly thirty years later when he was replaced by Paul Conrad.
Russell won a Pulitzer Prize in 1946 for his cartoon "Time to Bridge That Gulch" that was published on November 30, 1945 and depicted the gap between the United States and Russia. Sigma Delta Chi presented him with the Distinguished Service Award in 1948, 1950 and 1951. He also received the Headliners' Award for editorial cartoons in 1949, and from 1949 to 1962 his work was annually recognized by the Freedoms Foundation award. His other honors include the Christopher Award (1953) and an award from the U.S. Treasury (1960 or 1958?). At UCLA, Russell was named the Edward A. Dickson Alumnus of the year in 1951. Russell was a member of the National Cartoonists Society and the Association of American Editorial Cartoonists.
On December 18, 1963 Bruce Russell died of a heart attack in Los Angeles, California.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Bruce Russell Papers contain original artwork, correspondence, memorabilia, the artist's idea file, clippings and writings. The collection documents the Russell's career as a cartoonist and his work in several genres with material from the early 1920s through his death in 1963. It also includes original works by other cartoonists, often inscribed to Russell.
Cartoon clippings provides examples of Russell's published work. Items are arranged within categories that reflect the development of Russell's career: college and other early work, comic strips and features, editorial cartoons (mostly from the Los Angeles Times), Hollywood and theater, Los Angeles Times work (excluding editorial cartoons), and sports cartoons. Samples of his early work include clippings from The California Pelican, Southern Alumnus, and College Humor. His comic features include The Week in Review and Cartoonews, as well as the strips Good Old Chump and Rollo Rollingstone.
Editorial cartoons prepared daily for the Los Angeles Times between 1928 and 1963 form the largest part of the clippings section. Clippings of editorial cartoons from 1946 to 1963 are mostly cut from the Times editorial page and are substantially complete, arranged chronologically to the day. There is a gap between mid-July 1952 and December 1953.
As seen in both the clippings and the original drawings (see below), Russell's editorial work paralleled the generally conservative editorial viewpoint of the Los Angeles Times. Recorded by Russell's pen were two major wars and the harbingers of the war in Vietnam, the beginnings of space exploration, the emergence of new political leaders, among them the Californian Richard Nixon, and life in southern California as the area grew in economic and political influence. Besides the national and international events that provided topics for his editorial comment, there also recur in his cartoon work references to rising taxes and Los Angeles politics, as well as many public service themes: traffic safety, the scouting movement, U.S. savings bonds, and charitable fund drives. During these years he developed a number of stylistic devices: the shrouded skeleton, an oafish Mars, the impoverished taxpayer dressed in a barrel, Tweedledum and Tweedledee, punning cartoon titles, the personifications John Q. Public and Miss Democracy, map outlines of political boundaries used metaphorically, and, from World War II, a maniacal Hitler, a slovenly Mussolini, and a fierce stereotype of the Japanese.
Correspondence contains a small amount of both incoming and outgoing correspondence. Correspondents of interest include Richard Nixon, Eleanor Roosevelt, and staff at MGM and Collier's. Subjects include acceptance notices for submitted artwork, requests for original cartoons and notes thanking the artist for his cooperation in charitable drives.
The Idea file series contains folders of illustrations, mostly clippings, as well as sketches, photographs, and published cartoons, that constitute a working reference file used by Russell in his work. The subject headings as they appear on the folders are Russell's own, except for headings in brackets. There are folders for political figures and other notables, Russell trademarks such as Tweedledum and Tweedledee and his characterization of the Roman god Mars, and traditional symbols as the donkey and the elephant, bulls and bears, the eagle, Father Time, and Uncle Sam. There is also a folder of clippings of work by other cartoonists.
Memorabilia contains a variety of material, primarily related to Russell's career. Included here are his diploma from cartooning school before he entered the University of California, awards, photographs of Russell and his family, and autographed photographs of notables including California political figures Edmund ("Pat") Brown, Goodwin Knight, Norris Poulson, James Roosevelt, labor leader John L. Lewis, Edward R. Stettinius, Jr., Arthur E. Summerfield, Raymond Moley, Senator Harry L. Byrd, and the cartoonists Rube Goldberg and George McManus. Also included here is promotional material, clippings of articles about Russell, exhibition information, a copyright registration card and miscellaneous proofs.
Original drawings, which spans more then seventy years, is subdivided into drawings by Russell and drawings by others. Original artwork by Bruce Russell spans his professional career, from early sketches in the 1920s to some of his last editorial cartoons. Some pieces of his non-editorial work are signed with the name "Bruce Barr." Most of this work was done for the Los Angeles Times. There are over 650 finished drawings by Russell, including more than 240 editorial cartoons and over 300 drawings for the comic strip Rollo Rollingstone. There are also 50 pencil sketches for editorial cartoons. Also worth noting are Russell's Hollywood and theatre illustrations. A topical index to Russell's original editorial cartoon art may be found at the end of this inventory.
Original drawings by other artists contains more than 160 pieces of art by fellow cartoonists and artists. Many are inscribed to Russell. Among the editorial cartoonists represented are Gib Crockett, Herblock, Jim Ivey, Bill Mauldin, Carey Orr and Vaughn Shoemaker. Work by the cartoonists Al Capp, Rube Goldberg, Jimmy Hatlo, and George Herriman is also present, along with a color cell from a Woody Woodpecker animation and a Charles Schulz "Peanuts" strip from 1955. There are also several cartoons by unidentified artists.
Writings consists of notes about the comic strip Rollo Rollingstone and typed questions prepared for Russell's appearance before a State Department and Pentagon panel in 1963.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoon clippings are subdivided by type and within that arranged in roughly chronological order. Correspondence is arranged in chronological order. Idea files are alphabetical by subject. Original drawings are subdivided into those by Russell and those by other artists; within that, Russell's are further subdivided by type and then arranged alphabetically by caption, while those by other artists are arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists including many of whom's work is included in the original drawings series of this collection. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Russell, Bruce, 1903-1963.; Los Angeles Times (Firm); Rollo Rollingstone (comic strip); Cartoonews.; The Week in Review.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc.; Editorial cartoons -- California -- Los Angeles.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; World politics -- 20th century -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Theater -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Sports -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Awards.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Comic strips.; Correspondence.; Editorial cartoons.; Illustrations.; Memorabilia.; Photographs.; Sketches.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Photographs and cartoon clippings, gift of Miss Maxine Russell, 1964.
Original cartoons, cartoon clippings, and other items, gift of Mrs. Bruce Russell, 1966.
Five original Bruce Russell cartoons, gift of Miss Minnette L. Frohlich, 1971.
"Practice Ground for Three Chopsticks?", gift of Robert Payne, 2009.
Inventory
- Cartoon clippings
  - College and other early work
    - Los Angeles Evening Herald work, circa 1922 (Box 1)
    - Other, circa 1922-1931; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Comic strips and features
    - Aunt Polly, undated (Box 1)
    - The Battle Front, 1931 (Box 1)
    - CartooNews, circa 1934; 4 folders (Box 1)
      See also Original art: Comic sctrips and features: CartooNews below.
    - Embarrassing Moments, 1928-1932 (Box 1)
    - Good Old Chump, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Hot Water, 1934? (Box 1)
    - Not Far From Broadway, circa 1929 (Box 1)
    - Olde Tyme Almanack, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
    - Review and Preview, circa 1930 (Box 1)
    - Rollo Rollingstone, 1931 (Box 1)
      See also Original art: Comic sctrips and features: Rollo Rollingstone below.
    - Starr, Reporter, undated; proof sheet, dailies (Box 1)
      See also Original art: Comic sctrips and features: Starr, Reporter below.
    - "The Week in Review", 1929-1933; undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - "Wynndebagg, the Ipecac Candidate", 1934? (Box 1)
  - Editorial cartoons
    - Editorial cartoons, 1928; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 2)
    - Editorial cartoons, early 1930s; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 2)
    - Editorial cartoons, 1931-1940; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 2)
    - Editorial cartoons, Jan 1941-Dec 1947; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 3)
    - Editorial cartoons, 1948-1950; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 4)
    - Editorial cartoons, 1951-Jul 1952; 1954; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 5)
    - Editorial cartoons, 1955-1957; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 6)
    - Editorial cartoons, 1958-1960; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 7)
    - Editorial cartoons, 1961-Mar 1963; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 8)
    - Editorial cartoons, Apr-Dec 1963; undated; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 9)
    - Editorial cartoons, undated; from the Los Angeles Times (Box 10)
    - Editorial cartoons drawn for other publications or as donations, 1930-1941 (Box 10)
  - Hollywood and theater illustrations
    - Miscellaneous, 1927-circa 1934; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, oversize, 1927-circa 1934 (Oversize 1)
  - Los Angeles Times work
    - "Among Ourselves" cartoons, 1931 (Box 2)
    - Times Sunday Magazine covers, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
    - Times Sunday Magazine illustrated pages, 1933-1934 (Box 2)
    - Times Sunday Magazine illustrations, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous illustrations, 1927-1933 (Box 2)
  - Sports features
    - "Following the Ball with Bruce Russell", 1932-1933 (Box 2)
    - Small-format sports cartoons, circa 1927 (Box 2)
    - "Sportoons", 1929 (Box 2)
    - Sports strips, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous illustrations, 1927-circa 1934; 5 folders (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - [General], 1922-1928 (Box 10)
  - [General], 1930-1934 (Box 10)
  - [General], 1942-1946 (Box 10)
  - [General], 1958 (Box 10)
  - [General], 1961-1963 (Box 10)
  - [General], undated (Box 10)
- Idea files
  - Airplanes (Box 11)
  - Ammunition (Box 11)
  - Animals, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Armor (Box 11)
  - Army, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Art (Box 11)
  - Artype Catalog (Box 11)
  - Automobiles (Box 12)
  - Autos and airplanes (Box 12)
  - Axes (Box 12)
  - Ballet (Box 12)
  - Barbers (Box 12)
  - Barrels and baskets (Box 12)
  - Baseball (Box 12)
  - Basketball (Box 12)
  - Bears (Box 12)
  - Bells (Box 12)
  - Bicycles (Box 12)
  - Birds, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Boats (Box 13)
  - Books (Box 13)
  - Bottles (Box 13)
  - Boxing (Box 13)
  - Brooms (Box 13)
  - Buildings, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Bulls (Box 13)
  - Cameras (Box 13)
  - Car and truck pictures, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Car and truck reference file (Box 13)
  - Car and truck reference pictures (Box 13)
  - Cards (Box 13)
  - Cartoon clips (Box 13)
  - Cartoon fantasies (Box 13)
  - Cartoons (Box 14)
  - Castro (Box 14)
  - Cats (Box 14)
  - Cavemen (Box 14)
  - Children (Box 14)
  - China (Box 14)
  - Christmas (Box 14)
  - Churches (Box 14)
  - Churchill (Box 14)
  - Circus (Box 14)
  - Clocks (Box 14)
  - Color cartoons (Box 14)
  - Comic Strips (Box 14)
  - Cooks (Box 14)
  - Costumes, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Cowboys (Box 15)
  - Cows (Box 15)
  - Cuts (Box 15)
  - Devil (Box 15)
  - Dewey (Box 15)
  - Dinosaurs (Box 15)
  - Dishes (Box 15)
  - Divers (Box 15)
  - Diving (Box 15)
  - Docks (Box 15)
  - Doctors (Box 15)
  - Dogs (Box 15)
  - Donkeys (Box 15)
  - Dragons (Box 15)
  - Ducks (Box 15)
  - Eagles (Box 15)
  - Egypt (Box 15)
  - Eisenhower (Box 15)
  - Elephants (Box 16)
  - Emblems (Box 16)
  - Eskimos (Box 16)
  - Factories (Box 16)
  - Farming (Box 16)
  - Father Time (Box 16)
  - Firemen (Box 16)
  - Fish (Box 16)
  - Fishing and boats (Box 16)
  - Flags (Box 16)
  - Flowers (Box 16)
  - Flowers, fruit, and food (Box 16)
  - Food (Box 16)
  - Football (Box 16)
  - Foreign policy (Box 16)
  - France (Box 16)
  - Franco (Box 16)
  - Furniture (Box 16)
  - Garner (Box 16)
  - Germany, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Giraffes (Box 17)
  - Globes (Box 17)
  - Graves (Box 17)
  - Grindstones (Box 17)
  - Guns (Box 17)
  - Hands, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Hands and feet (Box 17)
  - Hats (Box 17)
  - Heroes of peace (Box 17)
  - Hippopotamuses (Box 17)
  - Hitler (Box 17)
  - Homes (Box 17)
  - Horses, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Idea clippings (Box 17)
  - India (Box 17)
  - Indians (Box 18)
  - Insects (Box 18)
  - International (Box 18)
  - Iran and Turkey (Box 18)
  - Jails (Box 18)
  - Japan (Box 18)
  - Kennedy, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Lambs (Box 18)
  - Lamps (Box 18)
  - Lighthouses (Box 18)
  - Lincoln (Box 18)
  - Lions (Box 18)
  - Machinery (Box 18)
  - Mailboxes (Box 18)
  - Maps (Box 18)
  - Mechanical (Box 19)
  - Mexico (Box 19)
  - Mice (Box 19)
  - Microphones (Box 19)
  - Middle East (Box 19)
  - Miners (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
  - Missiles (Box 19)
  - Money (Box 19)
  - Monkeys (Box 19)
  - Moose and deer (Box 19)
  - Musical, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Nationalities (Box 19)
  - Navy (Box 19)
  - Nixon (Box 19)
  - Notables, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Oil (Box 20)
  - Peron (Box 20)
  - Pigs (Box 20)
  - Pilgrims (Box 20)
  - Pirates (Box 20)
  - Plows (Box 20)
  - Policemen (Box 20)
  - Political cartoons, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Political figures (1 of 2) (Box 20)
  - Political figures (2 of 2) (Box 21)
  - Poses (Box 21)
  - Poses, action (Box 21)
  - Punch (Box 21)
  - Rabbits (Box 21)
  - Railroads (Box 21)
  - Reptiles (Box 21)
  - Rollin Kirby cartoons (Box 21)
  - Romans (Box 21)
  - Roosevelt (Box 21)
  - Roosters (Box 21)
  - Royalty Safes (Box 21)
  - Scales (Box 21)
  - School (Box 21)
  - Scientists (Box 21)
  - Scouting (Box 22)
  - Seals (Box 22)
  - Seasons (Box 22)
  - Ships (Box 22)
  - Ships and railroads (Box 22)
  - Shoes (Box 22)
  - Skating (Box 22)
  - Skeletons (Box 22)
  - Skunks (Box 22)
  - Snails (Box 22)
  - Space capsules (Box 22)
  - Spain (Box 22)
  - Sports, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Squirrels (Box 22)
  - Stage (Box 22)
  - Stassen (Box 22)
  - Statue of Liberty (Box 22)
  - Steel and cranes (Box 23)
  - Stevenson (Box 23)
  - Stores (Box 23)
  - Stoves (Box 23)
  - Swords (Box 23)
  - Taft (Box 23)
  - Tanks (Box 23)
  - Telephones (Box 23)
  - Tigers (Box 23)
  - Track and field (Box 23)
  - Traps (Box 23)
  - Trees (Box 23)
  - Truman, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Turkeys (Box 23)
  - Tweedledum and Tweedledee (Box 23)
  - Uncle Sam (Box 23)
  - Uniforms (Box 23)
  - Ventriloquism (Box 23)
  - Wagons (Box 23)
  - Washington, George (Box 23)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 23)
  - Washington, D.C. (cont.) (Box 24)
  - Water (Box 24)
  - Weather (Box 24)
  - Windmills (Box 24)
  - Winter (Box 24)
  - Witches (Box 24)
  - Wolves (Box 24)
  - Women (Box 24)
  - World (Box 24)
- Memorabilia
  - Advertisements for Russell's work, 1931; 1962-1963 (Box 25)
  - Association of American Editorial Cartoonists program, 1961 (Box 25)
  - Awards, 1953; 1960-1961,; undated (Box 25)
  - Awards (oversize), 1947-1963 (Oversize 2)
  - Biographical material [MISSING 3/2/17], 1930; 1935,; 1951,; 1953,; 1963-1964
  - Brochures promoting Russell's work, 1930-1963; press kits for syndication sales (Box 25)
  - Brochures promoting Russell's work (oversize), 1930-1963; press kits for syndication sales (Oversize 2)
  - Christmas cards drawn by Russell, undated (Box 25)
  - Clippings about cartoonists (Box 25)
  - Clippings about Bruce Russell, 1931-1934; 1960-1963,; undated (Box 25)
  - Clippings of articles by Russell, 1929; undated (Box 25)
  - Clippings of cartoons by others, 1930s (Box 25)
  - Clippings that mention Russell, 1932-1962; undated (Box 25)
  - Diploma from the Federal School of Applied Cartooning, 1921 (Box 25)
  - Donkey plaque, undated (Oversize 3)
  - Engraving plate and Mother's Day pin, undated (Box 25)
  - Exhibition clippings, 1943 (Box 25)
  - Exhibition photographs, 1937 (Box 25)
  - Exhibition programs, 1938 (Box 25)
  - Invitations, 1931; 1935; Russell's wedding; sorority function (Box 25)
  - Letters to the editor regarding Russell's work, 1941; undated (Box 25)
  - Obituary notices and cartoon tributes, 1963 (Box 25)
  - Occasional artwork by Russell, 1962; undated; miscellaneous printed material (Box 25)
  - Photograph of Russell, undated; working at desk (Oversize 9)
  - Photographs of Russell, undated (Box 25)
  - Photographs of the Russell Family, undated (Box 25)
  - Photographs of others, 1945; undated; signed and inscribed to Russell (Box 25)
  - Photographs of others, 1926-1962; undated; signed and inscribed to Russell; includes John Lewis (Oversize 1)
  - Prize-winning cartoons, 1952; undated; clippings (Box 25)
  - Proofs of editorial cartoons, 1960s (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1920s-1960s; printed material, photographs, press promotion of War Finance publication, clipping from George Herriman, copyright registration card (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Oversize 9)
- Original drawings
  - By Bruce Russell
    - College and other early work, 1926-1928; undated; 6 items (Oversize 9)
    - Comic strips and features
      - Big Boy, undated; 2 strips in 4 pieces (Oversize 2)
      - Boomer Biggins, undated; 17 items (Oversize 5)
      - CartooNews, undated; 6 folders (Oversize 4)
        See also Clippings: Comic strips and features: Cartoonews above.
      - Doctor Hooey, undated; 4 items (Oversize 5)
      - Hollywood Flash!, undated; includes proof sheet; 3 items (Oversize 1)
      - Rollo Rollingstone, 1930, Feb-Jul (Oversize 5)
      - Rollo Rollingstone, 1930, Aug-Dec (Oversize 6)
      - Rollo Rollingstone, 1931, Jan-Jun (Oversize 7)
      - Rollo Rollingstone, 1931, Jul-Dec (Oversize 8)
      - Rollo Rollingstone, 1932; 1934,; undated; 17 items (Oversize 8)
      - Romantic Roscoe, undated; 3 items (Oversize 8)
      - Starr, Reporter, undated; 7 items (Oversize 8)
        See also Clippings: Comic sctrips and features: Starr, Reporter above.
      - Tidbits, undated; 12 items (Oversize 4)
      - Week in Review, undated; 4 items (Oversize 2)
    - Daily Double, circa 1955; editorial cartoons series; 10 items (Oversize 12)
    - Editorial cartoons
      - Miscellaneous pencil sketches for editorial cartoons, undated (Oversize 1)
      - A, 1930; 1935,; 1956,; 1958,; 1963,; undated (Oversize 13)
        Adlai Stevenson stepped here (April 12 1956)
        Ah, the finish (circa 1935)
        All she'd need is the Smith vote (Nov. 10 1963)
        Alphabetical order (Nov. 15 1958)
        And a merry old soul is he! (undated)
        And start taking your coat off now (1930)
        And there aren't any holes in it (undated)
        Another moratorium? (undated)
        Another one of those child marriages! (undated)
        The assassin (undated)
        Aw, go on and get a shave! (July 16)
      - B, 1928; 1937,; 1958,; 1960,; 1962-1963,; undated (Oversize 13)
        Beard of the prophet (undated)
        The beard of the prophet (1937)
        Before you start for a summit... (Mar 6 1958)
        A black dachshund crossed her path (undated)
        Blank! (undated)
        Both: 'Well, what are you going to do about it?' (Dec. 26 1960)
        The Boys are at it again. 'Need any help?' (May 17 1928)
        Bumper crop (June 22 1962)
        But let's not put her out on a limb! (undated)
        But my heart belongs to big daddy (Aug. 10 1963)
        But there are some who didn't (undated)
      - C, 1929; 1936,; 1959-1963,; undated (Oversize 13)
        A cabinet, a crib and a big wastebasket (Nov. 30 1960)
        Calling out the class of '37! (1936)
        The car that parked overtime! (undated)
        The census is being taken! (undated)
        Cheshire cat (Aug. 3 1962)
        The chipsky on the shouldervitch! (undated)
        Christmas count up (Dec. 18 1961)
        The Christmas shoppers (undated)
        The classroom! (undated)
        The cloud with the silver lining! (undated)
        Cold facts (1929)
        ColumbU.S. (Oct. 12 1963)
        'Come to order and fasten your clothespins' (May 29 1962)
        The comic valentine (undated)
        Coming lei day (July 19, 1959)
        The cooking's starting early! (undated)
        Court plaster (Oct. 11 1961)
        The crest of this wave can't be too high! (undated)
        Crowded off (undated)
      - D, 1952; 1961-1962,; undated (Oversize 13)
        Dead eye (May 15 1961)
        The deadlines (Dec. 18 1962)
        Death's-Headline (Apr. 23 1962)
        Divorced (undated)
        The dog without a country! (undated)
        The 'don't care' hare and the Easter bunny (undated)
        Dove with a vulture's wings (circa 1952)
      - E, 1957-1958; 1961-1963,; undated (Oversize 13)